to the ICA Credential Life Insurance
Company Limited FY 2026 earnings
conference call. As a reminder, all
participant lines will be in the
listenon mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your touchstone phone. I now hand the
conference over to Mr. Anub Bakshi, MD
and CEO of ICAC Predential Life
Insurance Company Limited. Thank you and
over to you, sir.
>> Thank you. Good afternoon and welcome to
the results call of ICA Potential Life
Insurance Company for the year ended
March 31st, 2026.
I have several of my senior colleagues
with me on this call. Amit Pala, chief
products and distribution officer. Jiren
Salian, CFO, Jeie, chief service
delivery. Manish chief investment
officer, Shraik appointed auri and hir
chief investor relations officer. We
also joined today by Amish Banker. Amish
started his career in branch operations
and has a deep understanding of the
customer life cycle and organization
processes and systems. He is currently
the chief operations officer and would
be taken over will be taking over as
chief distribution officer from Amit
Pala. Amirit as you would have noted in
the exchange update is moving on from
the company having spent more than two
decades in the ICA group. We wish him
all the very best for his future
endeavors.
Let me start with some key updates on
the regulatory front. We welcome the
ideas transition to India which will
align our financial reporting with
global standards. This shift enhances
transparency and market comparability
ensuring that our financial statements
reflect an improved pictures of value
accretion.
On the economic front in FI 2026, the
Indian economy displays resilience while
navigating external turbulence due to
trade tariffs and geopolitical
conflicts. The stability was anchored by
direct tax relief, GST reforms and RBS
supportive monetary policy stance aimed
at stimulating the domestic consumption.
As a company, we also exhibited agility
and resilience, achieving a VNB of 26.29
billion with VNB growth of 10.9% in FI
2026 and work to deliver long-term value
to our shareholders. Our VNB margin
stood at 24.7%
as compared to 22.8% in FI 2025.
That grew strongly by 34.6% yearonear to
16 billion.
Life insurance products particularly the
retail protection segment received a
significant boost partly added by the
GST reform effective September 2025
the retail some assured growth for the
industry were higher by 2.5 times in the
postreform period as compared to the
pre-reform period
in the current year our retail new
business reached 4.5 trillion led by
50.9% year-on-year growth in retail
protection in H2 to 2026 demonstrating
our dominant position in this segment.
In the savings category, despite the
external volatility of FI 2026, our AP
remained steady and similar to the
previous year. New business premium
registered a year-on-year growth of
approximately 10%. 248.10 billion in FI
2026. Our business growth has also been
delivered on a foundation of risk and
prudence and is exhibited in our
resilient balance sheet. In FI 2026, we
maintain an industryleading claim
settlement ratio of 99.3%.
With an average turnaround time of 1.1
days, our early claims ratio stood at
22% best-in-class in the industry,
highlighting our focus on quality
business source over the years. Our
13-month persistency stood at 84.5%. Our
solvency ratio stood at 227.3%
well capitalized and much ahead of the
regulatory requirement of 150%.
We continue to maintain our track record
of not having a single non-performing
asset in our investment portfolio since
inception of our company.
We remain committed to deliveries
delivering superior value to our
customers by leveraging economies of
scale and aligning our cost structure
closely with our evolving product mix.
Notably, the technology and digital
solutions have enabled us to increase
efficiency resulting in a reduction of
40 basis point to 12.1% in our savings
cost to premium ratio during FI 2026.
Our AM stood at 3.14 trillion and our
total infor
16.9% year-onear to 46.11 trillion at
March 31st 2026. In the same year, our
embedded value grew by 10.5% yearonear
to reach 529.89
billion. To summarize, this year as we
celebrate 25 years of its service to our
customers, we would like to reaffirm our
commitment to deliver sustainable VN
growth by balancing business growth,
profitability, and risk and prudence.
Towards this, we believe all the
necessary levers continue to be
available with us. Thank you and I'll
now hand it over to Amit to take you
through the business updates.
>> Thank you Anoo. Uh good afternoon
everyone. As Anut mentioned the past
year was defined by changing
macroeconomic landscape shaped by both
global and domestic shifts and
additionally we also had a relatively
high base of last year particularly in
H1. Quarter 3 onwards the growth
momentum returned with retail AP growth
of 10% yearonair. This positive
trajectory sustained throughout quarter
4 until renewed geopolitical disruptions
emerged in March 2026.
Despite these disruptions, we managed to
deliver growth in quarter 4 with AP
registering 9.54%
year-on-year growth. On a fullear basis,
AP grew by 2.2% yearonear to 106.41
billion.
Coming to product wise performance, our
core focus area retail protection grew
by 60.5% yearonear in quarter core uh
resulting in a fullear growth of 32.3%.
With an estimated 13% of the addressable
population currently being covered
through retail protection, we believe
this segment offers a multi-beckadel
growth opportunity.
Group protection which includes credit
life and group term business grew by
7.1% yearon year in FI26.
Within that group term business grew by
14.6% year on year and credit life
business grew by 1.8% yearon year. MFI
segment which witnessed challenges at
start of the year has seen recovery from
quarter 3 onwards. Link business AP grew
by 1.6% 6% yearon year in FI26 impacted
by volatile equity markets. 2year CGR
for link business AP stood at 14.2%.
We continue to focus on increasing the
contribution from high units in this
segment. Such products are less impacted
by market volatility thereby providing
stability to link category to a large
extent.
The non-link savings AP grew at 15.4% 4%
year on year for the first 9 months.
Last year in quarter 4 we launched a new
product in the segment which had a very
good response. This year quarter 4 as
business from that product normalized
non-link business has declined year on
year in quarter 4. On fullear basis the
business and contribution from non-link
savings business is at similar level
last year. Annuality business 4year
caggr stood at approximately 20%. This
business has stabilized at around 7% of
our retail mix. Group funds business
grew by 26% yearonear. Now let me talk
about channel wise performance. Agency
channel AP stood at 26.86 billion and
direct channel AP stood at 14.30 billion
in FY 2026. Together these channels
contributed 47.4%
overall retail AP. These channels have
declined this year primarily due to the
high base of link and annuality
businesses in the previous year. In the
agency channel, growth trajectory has
shown consistent sequential improvement
throughout this year. As a strategic
priority, we have been investing in the
channel from a long-term perspective.
Our road map centers on microarket brand
strategy and using technology and
analytics as a productivity leader. By
equipping agents with tools and
analytics to automate administrative
task they can pivot their focus towards
high value revenue generating
activities. In the direct channel focus
will be to deepen NI segment through
gift city and scale up online channel
through differentiated operates. Bank
assurance channel grew by 3.6% yearon
year and contributed 29.8% to total AP
partnership distribution channel grew by
23.4% yearonear and contributed 13.2% to
AP mix in FI26.
In bankership distribution channel our
focus continues to be on adding new
partnerships and improving the share of
shop in each partnership. Group business
grew by 14 and a half% yearon year and
contributed 18.3% to the overall AP mix
in FI 2026.
Today we have the strength of 2.42 lakhs
advisers, 53 bank partnerships with
access to more than 26,400 bank branches
and 1500 plus non-bank partnerships. To
summarize, our primary focus will be to
drive business growth through a
microarket strategy in proprietary
channels. By deepening our distribution,
we shall gain access to a wider range of
customer profiles which enhances our
ability to seamlessly shift between
product segments as per macro
environment. We believe this will help
us keep our product and channel mix
balanced and deliver sustainable growth
irrespective of the market environment
over the long term. I will now hand it
over to Direin to talk you through the
financial upgrade.
>> Thank you Amit. Good afternoon everyone.
Let me start with some efficiency
related aspects. As you're aware, we
have undertaken various cost
optimization initiatives in the past two
years to make our cost structure aligned
to our prevailing product mix. One of
them being the use of a IML which is
being embedded across the entire
customer journey that is driving
targeted demand generation, automated
underwriting, include renewal retention,
enhanced customer service and effective
claims investigation.
Upsell programs and digital lead
conversion, both supported by machine
learning models, continue to contribute
to growth, while advanced fraud
detection and early claims
identification, help mitigate risk and
improve profitability. We have also
deployed AIE face matching between KYC
documents and customer images to reduce
fraud risk. Genai based categorization
of incoming customer emails has
significantly improved turnaround times
and AIdriven medical summarization is
enabling faster and more efficient
underwriting decisions. Further details
on usage of a IML across our processes
is shown on slide number 36 of the
presentation.
As can be seen on slide 12, the various
productivity enhancements have helped in
reducing cost to premium ratios for our
savings line of business by 40 basis
points to 12.1% in FI 2026. This cost
reduction is after accounting for
unavailability of input tax credit which
is effective September 22nd, 2025.
Our total cost to premium ratios for FI
2026 stood at 18.2% and remained stable
at previous year's levels.
The company's profit after tax grew by
34.6% year-onear to rupees 16 billion in
FI 2026 primarily driven by higher
investment income from shareholder
funds. This includes a gain of rupees
1.14 billion realized from sale of 100%
equity shareholding in ICA pension fund
management company which was ear while
called ICA potential pension funds
management company limited excluding the
sale transaction that grew by 25%
year-on-year in FI 2026.
Our solveny ratio continues to be strong
at 227.3%.
The improvement in solveny is primarily
due to increase in profit after tax and
realization from sale of substitution.
Our assets under management stood at
rupees 3.13
trillion as of March 31st 2026.
Value of new business VNB grew by 10.9%
year-onear to rupees 26.29 billion. As
you are aware, our focus is on growing
the absolute BMBB which we have been
able to achieve through improvement in
product mix and operational efficiencies
even after accounting for the
unavailability of input tax credit. BNB
margin expanded by 190 basis points
yearon year to 24.7%
in the current year. Margin expansion
has been led by improvements in new
business profile and economic assumption
changes.
Protection mix for the year has
increased by 2.2% 2% year-on-year to
17.9%.
Additionally, we have also been working
towards improving the profitability of
each line of business through longer
tenure policies, higher summershot
multiples, and increasing rider
attachments. The policy term on the
savings line of business has increased
from 26 years in FI 2025 to 29 years in
FI226.
Retail summur has grown by 35%
year-on-year in the current year. The
expansion was offset by operating
assumption changes which is primarily
due to unavailability of input tax
related on individual businesses and
some updates to persistency. As shown in
slide 16, our embedded value grew by
10.5% yearonear to rupees 529.89
billion at March 31st 2026.
Our embedded value operating profit
stood at rupees 57.02 billion in FI
2026.
The B break up of the EVOP is as
follows. Unwind contribution for FI 2026
is 7.4% of the opening EV. VNB of 26.29
billion rupees is 5.5% of the opening
EV. Unwind and VNB together constitutes
12.9% of the opening EV. Operating
assumption change is 0.5% of the opening
EV negative and primary on account of
unavailability of input tax credit and
some updates to persistently as I
mentioned earlier both mortality and
experience expense variance are positive
for the year and broadly in line with
our expectations
persistency variance is a negative 2.64
64 billion rupees which is largely on
account of the 100% premium back annuity
product where the persistency experience
fell short of long-term assumptions. As
you're aware, it was an industry first
product and coincided with regulatory
discussions aimed at increasing
increasing surrender values for
traditional savings products during the
year. Given the market volatility and
tight liquidity scenarios where market
returns were negative, we believe that
customers use the amount for withdrawals
in times of need. While we ensure that
economic benefits were safeguarded from
our company's perspective, the future
earnings which is part of EV was
impacted due to the draws. Consequently,
the ROE for financial year 2026 stands
at 11.9%.
The total economic and investment
variance is um negative 7.78 billion
rupees due to a shift in the yield curve
and equity market movements. Our VNP and
EV have been reviewed independently by
millin advisors LLP and their opinion is
available in the results pack submitted
to the exchanges. Further sensitivity
details are available on slide 17. This
concludes the financial performance.
I will now hand it over to Judjit to
talk you through the ESG updates. Thank
you Din. I I will be sharing the salient
aspects of our ESG journey. We continue
to retain the highest ranking in the
Indian life insurance industry as per
leading global and Indian PH rating
agencies. We're also delighted to share
that during Q42026,
we received the platinum award for our
ESG report for 2025 and the vision
awards organized by the League of
American Communications Professionals.
We were also recognized among India's
top 60 most sustainable companies by
business world. I will now share the key
highlights under each of the year focus
areas. Environment. We continue to look
at ways and means of reducing our carbon
footprint by erupting green energy
across various branches in across India.
Apart from the lead platinum certificate
which is a green building rating for the
companies our headquarters here. We have
also got the IGBC platinum green
building certification for four other
branches.
on responsible investing. We are signary
to the UN principles for uh responsible
investment. We have completed our third
annual reporting on responsible
investing activities and we shall
continue to remain committed to promote
ESG factors in our investment decisions.
Um on the diversity front, our gender
diversity is now at 30%. And we shall
continue to strive to improve it from
here. Uh as far as communities are
concerned, our goal has been to increase
financial inclusion through specially
designed micro insurance products
targeting socially and economically
weaker sections and we have covered 53.8
million rice as of March 31st 2026.
This year we settled more than three
lakh retail and group claims with an
overall claim settlement ratio at 99.8%.
On the CSRs front through ICA foundation
we have established cleaning labs at
four locations to facilitate advanced
industry aligned skill training. While
in the area of healthcare we supported
the Indian cancer society to conduct
surgeries for almost more than 90
patients governance. Our board has a
majority of independent directors
enabling the separation of a board's
supervisory role from executive
management. I would like to reaffirm our
commitment again to create a culture
that embraces sustainability and goes
beyond goals and targets. Thank you very
much. We're now happy to take any
questions that you may have.
Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask a question may press
star and one on their touchdown
telephone. If you wish to remove
yourself from the question queue, you
may press star and two. Participants are
requested to use handsets while asking a
question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles.
We'll take a first question from the
line of Swarnab Mukharji from BNT
Securities. Please go ahead.
>> Hi sir. Uh good afternoon. Uh and
congrats on a good set of numbers. Um so
I have three uh questions. First of all
just wanted to understand in terms of
growth how should we think about uh in
the upcoming year given that uh you know
the this particular year how the growth
has uh trended u I mean gives us a very
favorable base to grow uh so if I if you
could outline your strategy of how you
are thinking about FY27
and uh given that uh you know last year
uh you know there was this launch of PAR
product uh and you highlighted that
which would have led to a slower growth
in the non-link channel. Uh but uh you
know what are your thoughts on the
non-per category? How do you see it? And
parally also if you could provide us the
mix for PAR nonpar for the quarter. uh
that's one and uh then sir on the VNB uh
margin side if you could highlight you
know have uh you know all the
persistency changes that you are seeing
uh you experiencing has that been taken
into the assumptions or can something
incremental come or if you are observing
anything due to the cylinder value
regulation that you might want to
highlight and in that case then you know
how should we think about the VNB margin
uh numbers should we take the current
air numbers more a baseline uh if kind
of the product makes sustain. Uh so this
is uh yeah I think sir this is broadly
uh my queries if you could answer.
Thanks.
>> Hi Swa this is Dane here. Uh so let me
pick up some of your questions uh in
terms of growth for the next financial
year. I think this is quite a volatile
time at this stage. U and I'm sure you
would have seen the way the markets have
behaved over the last month of the
financial year. Uh I think this is still
going to be a bit of a wait and watch.
Uh you're right. Specifically for us, we
do have a base that is uh good for us,
but again it'll depend upon how things
shape up uh in the environment. Um so
it's a little early for us to commit as
to what the number should look like for
the rest of the year but rest assured
and the way that we're approaching the
problem is that we would continue to go
granular continue to understand who are
these customer segments that we should
be looking at what are the product fits
that we would need work with our
distribution channels to be able to
deliver the right proposition for
customers as well as shareholders that
uh objective and that uh process
continues there's no unwavering on that
front
coming to your second question in terms
of what is the split between PAR and
non-par for the year it's roughly 2 is
to1 ratio uh it's been broadly in that
range some quarters a little higher some
quarters a little lower but broadly in
the 2:1 range uh for the year uh coming
to your question third question which is
on uh the persistency experience see our
process around looking at assumptions
and experiences is to look at what is
temporary and what is permanent so and
We do this at every year uh towards the
end of the year in terms of how these
assumptions are shaping up. So whatever
is known at this point uh we will
incorporate as part of our uh assumption
setting. U if there are experiences that
we see are temporary in nature or they
pertain to quarantine portfolios, we
allow them to go through uh the
variance. uh so at this point we have
factored what we know on terms of
persistency in terms of mortality and
terms of expenses as part of our uh
margin so this essentially becomes the
baseline for us going forward
>> right very helpful just couple of
follow-ups on u you know two aspects one
is on the growth as you mentioned I
understand that this is a volatile year
but like if I were to look at from the
channel side also I mean this year's uh
growth has been primarily heavy lifted
by your partnerships so uh I mean what
would be uh you know what uh how shall
we think about say the other channels
for example agency this year has been
tipped so how uh how do you plan to
activate uh or go about uh driving that
channel I understand that banka given uh
you know the base of uh ICC bank uh
there may be a steadiness in that number
but particularly on the agency I wanted
to query and also like on the on the
persistency part in surrender value
related regulations are you seeing any
delta uh uh apart from the NVT product
that's what I wanted to understand.
Thanks.
>> Yeah. So on the uh early experience of
surrender value products I am we're not
seeing anything too different but it's a
little too early to call because you
only got about 5 to 6 months of
experience and we had allowed the whole
year to pan out for that.
Yeah. In terms of growth you're right
agency has not had a great year in that
sense the growth has not been great. to
that extent it does form a a fairly uh
good base for us into the coming year
but like I mentioned we'll continue to
work at it granularly understand what
are these micro segments that we need to
go after and uh work with that
>> all right thank you thanks uh all the
best for
>> thank you we'll take our next question
from the line of supra team duta from
Jeff please go ahead
>> um hi thanks a for the opportunity. Uh I
have three questions you know starting
with the growth aspect. Uh could you
help us understand how customer behavior
has changed with respect to products
post the start of this Middle East war?
Are you seeing any increase in demand
for non-par policies in this current
environment and you know how are you
seeing the demand of ULIPS um in late
March and early April if you could give
us some color around the trends that
would be helpful because what I see is
in March despite the lower base the
agency channel has declined uh and this
channel should ideally have lower unit
exposure so you know trying to
understand what's happening there uh on
the margin bit Um what I wanted to
understand is despite the rise in group
funds in fourth quarter uh ICF has
witnessed a sequential rise in margins
uh is this a function of higher yields
in some of the nonpart products and you
know potentially uh protection as well
or is there some other driver here um
that we should look at and lastly coming
to the India's transition now with India
rolling out from 1st of April wanted to
understand would you be sharing the
indas accounts from next quarter and how
would the bits compare share with the
CSM in force if you could give us some
color and you know how does this change
your capital position as well u you know
if you could give us some color on that
that also would be well thank you
>> hi super uh let me cover India's first
uh so yes uh technically we are live we
should be live with India's uh but as
approved by the board we will be seeking
boardbearance for a year uh one of the
more fundamental points are that uh some
of the uh decisions around how
uh inputs could be provided for
computing uh the CSM. I think we still
await some clarity from the joint expert
group. Uh the other thing also is that
uh this is too short a time for us to
transition into INDS given the fact that
we are uh typically live with our
results by the first 15 days of the uh
quarter. Uh so we would need some time
to be able to gear our systems up to be
able to manage the transition there.
uh in in terms of uh the capital
position uh I believe the regulator
still wants us to use the first solveny
uh formulas. So until we wait to see how
the RBC gets implemented uh we would
continue with our current solveny basis
on which we're quite strong at 220%.
Uh coming to your second question that
you had asked which is on margin. Uh the
margin support has largely come in by
the growth and protection that you can
see for the current quarter which has
been quite strong. U in addition to of
course all the improvements to
profitability that we've been doing
across all other savings lines of
business as I'd mentioned earlier.
>> Uh your first question was on what are
the upcoming trends. Uh little to early
to call uh Supratim then get it uh
settled. I do believe that the the war
in West Asia has to some extent impacted
new business sales in the month of
March. Difficult to guess how much it
would be but uh clearly there has been
some impact.
>> U thanks a lot for this color. So just
wanted to understand had the impact been
more on unit or has it been across the
board uh slowdown in demand than late
March?
Uh it's been across the board except for
protection.
Okay. Understood. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Next question is from the
line of Shrea Shivani from Namora.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi. Uh good afternoon. Thank you
for the opportunity and uh
congratulations on a uh good set of uh
numbers. Uh I have two questions. Um
both on the EV walk. Uh first is uh the
operating assumption changes that we've
taken is it only the uh persistency
operating assumption or there are
certain changes you've done with
assumptions in mortality or expense etc.
And second is I mean it's the roe it's
at 11.9 now I mean even if I had assumed
a zero value for operating assumption
changes and a zero for uh persistency
variance instead of negative number I
would still be at a 12.9 or so. So what
is genuinely our uh steadystate roe that
we should assume um because we are we
are already under the cost of equity in
FI26 and how should I think about it for
for for that matter? Yes.
>> Hi Shya. Uh so committee your question
on operating assumption changes in EV as
I mentioned on my opening remarks it's
primarily on account of unavailability
of input tax credit and then some
updates to persistency. Now this entire
if you recall this conversation had
started in September as to the impact of
the uh unavailability of input tax
credits to GST reforms that has been the
bigger component out of uh this
operating assumption change.
>> Okay.
>> Right.
>> Right. Now uh coming to ROE uh yes this
without the assumption changes and
variance we're at the 13% range. Now
technically on a longerterm basis we
should still be at the 13 to 14% range
depending of course on how the uh yield
curve shapes up depending of course on
how we're able to grow VNV and that
becomes the two primary drivers of how
you determine ROV but from that sense
that should be live uh actually is live
this year and uh if we get the four bits
then we will go live on that next year
uh looking at returns on uh earnings
things will become much easier when you
look at the Indas numbers the ROE will
have less significance going forward.
>> Got it. Got it. So, so uh with India it
does not impact the ROE whatsoever but
probably we'll not be looking at the
ROVS going ahead is what your point of
view is right. Yeah, my sense is most
commentators and analysts would end up
looking at roies because then that would
be at least comparable to how the rest
of the market is or outside of
insurance. comparison becomes much
easier then u for want of any other
metric we are in this roe world at this
point
>> right and there is no impact whatsoever
of IFRS on the EV walk right nothing
from the even if say a risk based
solveny comes through nothing gets
changed in in this metrics right
>> no risk based solveny only determine
your capital position
>> correct okay nothing happens here yeah
all right Okay, there's any questions.
Thank you.
>> Thank you. We'll take our next question
from the line of P Jen from Otila Los.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi. Couple of questions. First on
if I look at the production business
premium growth exceeds the summer
growth. uh how how should we read that
whether you know uh it's um you know
more uh uh you know return of premium
products that has come in or now how how
should we kind of read that that's one
and second is more of a structural
question on the embedded value front
where you know in FI24 we had a
mortality variance then in FI25 we had a
assumption change and now we have a
persistency impact uh both in variance
as well as assumption I think you know
this has been constantly negative for us
over the past three fiscals. Uh how
should we kind of think about this going
and whether you know you have stress
tested
now uh to the extent that you know the
assumptions are more moderate or more
conservative uh and we could uh start
looking at more positive gradients or
assumption things is going just some
color on that. So that would be helpful.
Thanks.
>> So, uh pressure right when you look at
the protection some assured growth
that's been at uh about uh 48% uh some
assured on uh so the growth on retail
protection has been at higher at about
60%. Uh the retail new business summer
actually consists of both protection and
uh savings. So you will have to offset
the two together. So the retail
summation is not purely uh protection
because you see by by the fundamental
construct of products in India savings
products in India you end up providing
10x cover for most of our products
>> right
>> so that itself forms a summer shot that
comes on board right uh coming to your
question on embedded value and how we
look at how our assumptions are being
set frankly we run a very diversified
portfolio and our approach to setting
assumptions is to understand whether
these uh potential
differences between an assumption that
you have set and the resulting
experience that we see at this point is
that temporary or permanent.
Now the way you always look at the
businesses that come in is you group
them into cohorts and as you look at
each cohort you are trying to identify
whether uh cohorts look alike or do you
need to separate these cohorts and again
given the underlying variability of the
underlying uh diversity diversity of our
business you have to start looking at
each of these cohorts as they gain
meaningful size uh as there separation
you start to see assumption changes. If
I had a homogeneous portfolio then
ideally you should not see any
assumption changes at all or even
variances but given the diversity of the
underlying business that we bring you
have to look at cohorts and you have to
then start segregating coord as they
start to gain size and significance. So
in any case, as you look at the overall
experience and assumption changes, these
are marginal. Uh there have been points
in time when we had positive assumption
changes as well. Uh but overall, you see
that uh the business is being uh uh
ensured that the underlying assumption
that go reflective of what we see today.
>> Got that. And economic assumption
changes. Could you split that between
equity and debt?
>> It's largely debt. It's largely debt.
>> Almost all of it. God. Thank you so
much.
>> Thank you. We'll take our next question
from the line of Madukar Lada from JP
Morgan. Please go ahead.
>> Uh hi, good afternoon. Uh thank you for
taking my question. First uh you know um
see in the beginning of uh last year we
were sort of targeting uh above or at
least at par with private life insurance
uh uh you know retail uh AP growth. Uh
my I mean we've significantly sort of
underperformed that level. Uh now going
into uh sort of FI27 and onwards
um what do you think should should you
know be your target and uh how do you
think you will achieve that target like
if if you can sort of quantify uh you
know any sort of meaningful changes uh
that that you are doing uh that will you
know uh lead us to uh believe that uh
that we will be able to sort of you know
achieve uh higher uh retail uh retail AP
sort of growth right uh so that's my
first question um and and second uh also
if I look at persistency uh we seeing a
decline for the 161st month 13th month
and and also I think 25th month so
what's happening uh over there
u third
you know with significant um I mean you
interest rates have gone up, bond yields
have sort of gone up. Uh that should
help our uh margins. Um what
what will enable us to sell more non-par
or or uh you know as as a company what's
what what uh as a management uh how can
you sell more nonpar uh would be my my
question. Yeah, these would be my three
questions and also if you can split your
uh economic variance between debt and
equity. Yeah, thanks.
>> Hi Maduk, I just answer the question on
P. Uh the economic variance is largely
debt.
>> Uh okay,
>> in your first question you mentioned
about growth. U actually when you look
at the 2ear CG we're still in the range
of 78%. Yes, it is not in line with the
market but then we continue to see uh
work continue to work at at a granular
level to see what are those customer
segments that are available to us uh
through our distribution and where can
we generate growth from. So we are not
uh divorced from the market very clearly
we're looking at uh working at least at
the market and then look to work beyond
that. Uh largely when you look at the
market the 2-year growth seems to be in
the range of 10 to 11%. Uh we are in the
range of about 8 7 to 8%. So some work
left but we're not too far off. Uh you
asked another question on
>> to sort of interrupt on on that but you
know if you look at two year then that
may be the case but uh but if you come
to more recent time then uh last year's
uh number or 5.6 six would suggest that
uh we are losing some more ground uh
right so so in that sense
uh there'd be more to catch up moving
into FI278
>> yeah so Mikov we've discussed this
earlier also I think the focus for our
company is to be able to grow VNB in a
sustainable fashion right the large
component of VNB does absolutely come
from uh AP uh so as you rightly pointed
out yes two years slightly lower than
market But when I look at this year's
numbers in terms of AP at uh 2% growth,
BNB is at 11% growth. And you can see
there's consistency in the margin that
has held up all through the year. So I
think we're working at it sustainably to
work at it to see how we can deliver
growth in a sustainable format.
Your second question was on uh
persistency. 61st month we discussed
this earlier. This has been due to a
regulatory definition change.
uh 25th month uh is a new phenomena.
Yes, I think some of the uh spillover
from the 13th month is coming through to
the 25th month. At this point,
you had another question in terms of how
can we sustainably grow nonpar. I think
one of the challenges that we run up as
an industry is that our product uh does
get compared to what bank FD rates are.
uh in the current environment when bank
FD rates continue to be fairly steep uh
the product that we price the product
that we offer does not look as
attractive because very clearly the way
that we set up our products is to price
off the GC uh and so the return over the
longer term has to be built off the GC
uh there may be other considerations
that banks may be using to set up their
deposit rates uh but whenever there is a
dichotomy between the deposit rates and
the non-par IRS
uh then you will see customers swing
from one to another.
>> Okay, answer your question.
>> Yeah, that's that's helpful. Uh thanks a
lot and all the best.
>> Thank you. Next question is from the
line of Oman Sha from Banyan Tree
Advisor BMS. Please go ahead.
Mr. Oman Sha, your line is unmuted.
Please go ahead with your question.
Hello. Am I? Yes.
>> Yeah. Thank you for the opportunity. Uh
sir, uh one question was uh in FI24 we
were given VNB breakup uh among the
various segments. Uh if you can give
that number for FI26 and FI25 that would
be great.
>> Uh they align with the market on this
front.
Okay. Okay. Sure. Sure. That was very I
mean that usually quite helpful. Uh but
sure understand. Uh the second question
was the persistency decline in 13th
month code. Um has it does it have a
large part of annuity product or it's
across across segments?
>> A large part driven by annual. Uh there
are of course some segments that we have
seen some product channel cohorts that
have not performed on par.
>> Okay. Okay. And sir, when we have a
persistency which is worse than what you
were expecting, uh does it benefit the
VND or does it uh not benefit the VNDs?
>> Um it doesn't benefit. Uh so the way we
look at our assumption setting is that
we evaluate it at the end of the year.
We take a view as to which of these are
permanent impairments in that sense. Uh
for those we take an assumption change.
uh those that we believe are temporary,
we allow that to run through the
variance.
>> Okay. Okay. Sure, sir. And sir, uh
that's why uh so um no, I think that
that's all. I think I'm covered. I'll
get back in the queue. Thank you.
>> Thanks so much.
>> Thank you. We'll take our next question
from the line of Min Rajani from Nirmal
Bank. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Uh thank you for taking my
question. So I just uh most of my
questions were answered. I just had one
question. Now what happens to the
negotiations that uh that were going on
with uh the distributors on commission
and so on? Uh should we expect that uh
they are mostly done and if so then uh
you know um could we see agency doing uh
uh all all channels but especially
agency doing uh better uh in FY27 that
that was the only question I had. Thank
you.
Uh so you know the negotiations and
conversations with distribution be it
agency or otherwise is always on uh we
we look to offer the remineration that
is appropriate in line with the product
and the pricing that we have uh built uh
that is accredited to both shareholders
as well. So at all points in time this
is a continuous conversation. There is
never a start or a stop to this uh it
will continue. It has continued. It will
continue and just uh keep going forward
as well. So it is a continuous exercise
as we bring out new products and new
propositions. Uh we will continue to
work with our distribution to see how we
could deliver these products to the
relevant customer bases in a efficient
format.
>> Okay. So uh so no conclusion so far. I
mean uh this was uh this was ongoing for
some time. So um there's been no u what
do you say? Uh there will be no
agreement or something reached. uh how
should we look at it?
No,
>> agreements have been reached uh with all
our distribution. Uh we are where we are
and you are seeing the 24.7%
of the MV margin.
>> Understood. Thanks so much. Yeah.
>> Thank you. We'll take a next question
from the line of Sankit Koda from Aend
Park. Please go ahead.
>> Uh thank you. I have a few questions
just to start with. uh the uptake in the
margin in in the fourth quarter around
25.2 to uh can we attribute
predominantly to to the favorable yield
curve at least in the month of March and
and and and related to that uh in in the
VNB walk what we see as 250 basis point
addition to the VNB margin uh due to
economic variance is is it largely
because of the yield c benefit which
which played in the current year uh to
to to bump up the margins
uh when you look at the yield curve And
specifically in in the perspective of
non uh nonpar products and uh which also
includes protection uh one has to look
at what the pricing is and what the
yield curve is and what is the expected
margin that one wants out of it. So as
yield curves move depending upon your
underlying cost and of course you know
this year there has been an impact of
GST pricing has uh swung in that
direction. So if we have got a benefit
of the yield curves we would not have
changed we didn't change the pricing
u
in that fashion. Yeah, what you trying
to say that uh it did not uh change the
IR of the end consumer. I to the end
consumer despite the benefit and and
probably because of that I think the GST
impact to some extent got negated is
>> yeah so if you look at the VNB work
right what we have called out is the
movement across from 22.7 to 20 to 24.7
now here the product repricing whatever
that we have done is all sitting as part
of the new business profile
>> right and all the yield curve changes
are now part of the economic assumption
change so if I'm making any pricing
changes Yes, it has new product that
have come on board.
>> Understood. So no, my point was that you
got double benefit, right? Your product
mix also changed and and on top of it
you got an positive economic variance
number. Uh but naturally the impact of
minus 3.9 would be there in the VNB. So
so just wanted to assume that the permix
moved favorably and and also you took
the benefit of economic variance to
largely negate the impact of other
changes which might be largely related
to GSTP.
You take everything together Sankit. So
one we have been working very hard at
cost efficiencies across the years which
I spoke of earlier. So the benefit of
the cost efficiency is something that we
have taken on board as we've got done
our pricing. Uh because I'm getting cost
efficiencies I can continue to hold the
price as it is. Now this is Tetris
parabus
my some of my cost efficiency was
negated due to the GST impact. So
technically I should have changed my
pricing but then I also had the uh
improving yield curve which allowed me
to hold on to prices at that point.
Actually if you look at the entire
period there have been very marginal
price changes that too in certain
cohorts not across the board and I
believe we had answers answers the
question earlier as well one does one
did not expect onmass price changes to
happen and that has not happened.
Okay the reason I was asking this
question is that given given growth is
becoming soft a bit now and probably
yield curve becomes much more steeper
which which was very visible in the
month of March. Uh is it fair to say
that to to Philip the growth you you
will pass on some benefit to the
consumers and and and maybe maybe that
could play a role for for the growth and
and related to that point only that
given given we largely did only single
premium annity in the current year. Um
given given FRA lockins will be better
or bond forward lockins will be better.
uh will will you go back to deferred
attitude in a different format to to to
uh to to flip back the growth uh given
given the economics are in your favor or
or in your industry favor right now.
So uh let me give you a hypothetical if
the yield curve moves downward I will
repric
right uh your second point was around
regular pay annuity we do have regular
pay annuities and we continue to sell
those as well.
Yes, it swung a little more towards
single pay. Uh but uh we built our
regular pay and business as well and
we'll continue to sell that.
Uh understood understood and and uh and
two two more questions one question is
that uh given given it's almost uh uh 6
months closer to 6 months that GST
impact was taken on the protection uh uh
have we started repricing or industry
have started repricing the individual
protection business uh to to uh to uh to
to the extent of input credit not
available or or we still are on the old
pricing uh nature only and and and
related to Exactly given given we had a
very strong third quarter now fourth
quarter growth is still there but but it
is toning down a bit so so so the the
the impact of GST which was there in
third quarter is it fair to say that now
now it is coming back to normal demand
you saw the 60% growth in retail
protection in the quarter right so I
think what we've been doing is working
at this granularly to make sure that
protection growth continues
uh in terms of your question on how we
would look at pricing and have people
taken uh step changes I believe by and
large the industry has not taken step
changes you might have one or two
players have taken some minor increases
in uh prices onmass price changes that
to again to a degree of 1 to 3% across
the board most we have stayed away from
uh doing onmass price changes we have
taken cohorts and worked at those
cohorts where we need to make updates to
pricing that has been our perspective
how we could manage the entire
transition of GST and you've seen the
numbers come to in terms of 60% growth
I saw wrong number my bad actually I saw
only total protection growth numbers
also my bad 60 is a very solid number
>> yeah and lastly didn't then uh then if
you if you're okay to give uh the mix of
ULIP which has uh higher some assured
and and largely uh just to confirm back
again uh when in your PPT you gave
persistency 13 month persistency product
wise that is linked non-link and
naturally the non-lin part fell from
86.8 to 17 73.2 too. So, so I'm assuming
this is predominantly due to to the uh
zero surrender defer plan.
>> Yeah. So, the non non-link person drop
is due to the uh annuality plan there.
Uh and no, we've not called out the
split of the high performance.
>> Okay. Uh thanks. That's it. Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you. We'll take our next question
from the line of Nidesh Jen from Invest.
Please go ahead.
Uh thanks for the opportunity. Uh first
question is on EV split. So if I look at
March 25 EV split between whiff and uh
network uh for this uh in this
presentation is different from the last
year's presentation. So is there any
change uh in EV network methodology?
>> Yeah. So Nidesh you can refer to slide
63. Uh we've called that out and given
you a walk from 22 to 26. The key change
is that the shareholder share of the MTM
that's on the assets and derivatives in
the policy holder fund that's been
reclassified to with from the A&W that
has absolutely no impact on the EV just
a reclassification between within within
AW
and this is consistent with how the
market
>> classified in this
>> yes the MTM derivatives and assets and
derivatives of the policy holders has
been classified in the
>> okay sure
that's the reason for the change
Yeah, second question is that if I look
at agency business, last year key for it
declined 20%, this year again it has
declined on a lower base. So what is
exactly happening in this channel? Uh
why we are looking in terms of growth in
the agency channel specifically
>> uh in a large part due to the higher
base that we had of annuity in the
previous year that has held the uh pace
that we have to work against. Uh again
if you look at from a longer time frame
we still have a fairly decent uh growth
on agency but yes for the shorter term
it has been a bit of a challenge but
like as I mentioned earlier we are
looking at working granularly at agency
looking at these micro segments uh
building uh efficiency within the agency
distribution itself
>> and similarly China has also lagged in
lag in terms of growth
this year last year also I think Q4 it
was weak
>> yes that's right there is the base
effect with direct as well.
>> So in terms of expansion of these
channels, are we planning to add more
agents, open more offices or box? Uh I
just try to understand how are we trying
to let's say deliver growth in the
channels in FI27 and how are we planning
today for that growth.
So as I mentioned uh earlier we are
looking at these uh growth centers on a
datadriven platform especially with the
micro market branch strategy that we
have again using technology analytics as
productivity levers. Uh so we will
continue to work at it granularly uh and
then I'm not working on the fact that
the growth numbers have not been strong
uh we'll work at improving these as we
go down granularly into each of these uh
segments.
>> Sure. Third question is on nonpart
business. Since the yield curve has been
quite favorable uh why don't we offer
better IAS to the customers versus fixed
deposits have some cut on margins but
deliver better AP growth why we are not
doing that
see one of the things that they should
understand is that we get priced off the
GC uh I think by and large insurers in
India have been quite uh disciplined in
the approach to actually work off the GC
uh which may not have been the case uh
in geographies outside of India. Um the
pricing of deposits does not really
follow the GC uh threshold. Um so to
that extent at certain points in time
when deposit gets priced extremely well
uh relative to nonpar products which are
anyway built from a longerterm
perspective uh customers can swing from
one to another. Uh so if you were to
actually start to cut uh margins to be
able to deliver on growth on nonpar uh
it it may not be uh accurative to
shareholders.
The whole perspective that we carry
videsh is that again look at absolute
BNP. It's not a question of trying to
push one particular product versus
another. It's to identify what are these
opportunities that exist at this point.
And you're right in the sense that the
nonpar offers you a great opportunity in
sense that the yield curve is great is
there is steep and is able to give you a
good IRRa. Uh but the competition that
also comes about at least from a sticker
price comparison is FDS which are still
running a fairly steep rate. Uh so to
that extent uh the nonpar does get uh
subdued.
>> Sure. And lastly, you can share the uh
break up of group protection between
term protection group term and credit.
>> Yeah, that's in part of my Yeah, that's
in part of my next lectures uh of this
pack. Uh
>> sure.
>> Uh that's on slide 56.
>> Yeah,
>> 56. Okay, I will take it from Thank you.
Thank you.
>> Thank you. Next question is from the
line of GA from Shanpel Strategic
Advisors. Please go ahead.
Hi.
>> Uh yes, please go ahead.
>> Yes.
Yeah. Thanks so much for the
opportunity. Uh just want to have uh
couple of
>> I'm sorry to interrupt. So can I use
your handset mode please?
>> Yeah.
>> Uh yes, Mr. Owens.
>> Yeah. Go ahead. Go ahead, please.
>> Yeah. on slide 64 the easy work uh just
want to understand under the persistency
and the other varian 2.64 billion how
much is pertinent to BNB returning 526
sorry can you repeat the question again
>> yeah so we have a 2.64 64 billion uh
persistency and other variance in the EV
work. Right? I just want to understand
how much of that is uh attributed to uh
BM or AP policies written F26.
Almost none. Go.
>> This is for the pass.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Thank you so much.
>> Thank you.
Next question is from the line of Manus
Agraal from Bernstein. Please go ahead.
>> Hi. Uh my question relates to potential
regulations on commissions. A do we have
any understanding of what is happening
and when is it expected to happen and B
if there are like various levels of cuts
to commissions how would your margins
and your growth assumptions change?
Uh manus we are not aware of discussions
we do uh we do acknowledge that the
regulator asked for data which we have
provided but we have not heard anything
beyond that.
>> Okay. And second question, let's say the
regulator does something. Uh what would
be the sensitivity to growth and margins
on that front?
Um I don't know what the regulator's
thinking on that at this front. So it'll
be a little difficult to comment.
Understood. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
We'll take our next question from the
line of show Sharma from HDFC
Securities. Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi sir. Thank you for the
opportunity. I have a question for
Anupsir. Anupsir, if I look at our
retail business growth over last 2 three
years have not been that strong. If you
can help us understand what are the key
challenges which is impacting our
growth. Does our cost optimization
initiative which we have taken over the
last 2 three years are impacting our
growth trajectory and given market
remains like this for the entire year
and as we remain UL focused. How do you
internally plan growth and do you think
we can uh grow in line with the private
players and secondly we have been very
very very we have a very granular
distribution and agency plays a very
important role. The share of agency
channel has been coming down over the
last two years if you look at. So is it
because we have seen larger agents
moving to the competition or if there is
or there are any other challenges which
is impacting the growth of this channel.
So I think from a growth perspective I
think it might be useful to look a
slightly longer period and do a c of
growth and take volatility and base
effects into consideration. uh I don't
think that cost optimization comes in
the way of growth at all. In fact in our
industry I would say that uh since we
run largely two kinds of businesses one
is protectionled businesses which are
risk based businesses completely and
second is savings oriented business
which essentially either get priced off
the equity returns or get priced off GC.
In both cases what you can give to the
customer is less the margin and less uh
the commission cost.
So with that in context I think like in
all asset management businesses one has
to keep working on cost structures uh
both on your fixed cost as well as
optimizing on the submission cost and
distribution cost at least in areas
where it is not adding value but it is
giving topline. So there are always
pockets in large distributions where you
will see that there are largest payouts
and it is not given commensurate
margins or commensurate profits or
profit pools. So that is a constant area
of optimization that one has to do and
then on the protection side one has to
be focused on the risk uh which is early
claims and and make sure that your
underwriting is proper and your pricing
is better. uh so I don't think there is
anything sort of you know coming in the
way of growth we have to go more
granular and you have to get back growth
there are base effect and which is why
I'm saying and like Vir had earlier said
if you look at you know 2 years 3 years
uh CAGR even if you look at two years
CAGR we are slightly behind but we do
have to catch up I understand uh the
sentiment in the group uh that uh we
have to do more growth but our focus
like we have always said is absolute VNB
And uh in absolute VNB there are other
levers in addition to the AP. AP is a
very important lever. Uh not to say that
it is not but there are other levers
also which needs to be flexed uh to get
the VNB and make the whole business
model more robust. So there is nothing
sort of you know at this point of time
we don't think cost optimization
or things like that comes in the way of
growth at all.
And secondly is sir on the agency
channel how we plan to revive that
channel.
>> I think agency channel we have had some
large base effect uh you know two years
back and if you look at CGR a few years
which is running at 12 13%. And as the
base effect goes I think it will come
back and we are also certainly looking
at micro market uh agency. So hopefully
it will come back uh sooner than than we
think.
Okay, thank you and all the best.
>> Thank you. Next question is from the
line of Retika Dua from Bandan AMC.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah, sure. Thank you. Two questions on
the uh
sorry your voice is sounding muffled.
Can you use your handset mode please?
>> Am I
uh can you repeat the question? Yeah,
I'm just saying that there's two
questions. One is that on the Nesh was
on the reclassification
on the EV side. So while D you clarified
that it doesn't have a impact on the ED
but just uh could you just explain what
we have done and the objective of the
same to do it today that's one question
and the second question is that uh while
I know we are very early days of IFRS
but um uh just may hear your initial
thoughts as to how the KPIs would be
maybe you know in IFRS world so those
are the two questions thank you
>> right IFRS let's wait until it gets
implemented. Uh as we seek forbearance,
uh the current year will be on the
existing IGAP. Uh India's will form
financial information which will be
subsidy finan uh alternate financials.
So let's wait until uh that settles
because we'll have to recreate the OBS
and then look at quarterly financials as
they're being generated. Uh coming to
your first question on this
reclassification, this is just alignment
with what we're seeing the market at. U
nothing more than that. the total EV
does not change. Uh it's just alignment
and there is no specific guidance on
where this particular MTM is to sit. We
realize that uh it's better to align
with the way the market is presenting it
so that you have comparability.
>> And if you don't mind D could you just
explain the uh change again? I'll
obviously go through the presentation
but if if you don't mind could just
explain the change again.
>> Right. This is the mark to market on the
assets and derivatives uh of the policy
holder funds. Uh that is the component
that has been reclassified.
>> It's just the mark to market on the
assets and derivatives.
>> Sure. Thanks. Thanks. Thank you. I'm
done. Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you. Next question is from the
line of Deepan Kosh from city. Please go
ahead.
>> Hi. Uh good evening everyone. Uh so few
questions from my side. Um you know
first KM you mentioned uh on how you
really go about looking at assumption
changes and variances and on the
persistency and backbook. Uh now
specifically you mentioned that once a
select cohort kind of becomes uh becomes
meaningful from a size and scale uh
that's when you know uh you know the the
variability can come out to be a
meaningful number from a EV perspective
in case there are some uh differences
between assumptions and uh realities of
life. Now on that backdrop you also
mentioned that uh you know uh bearing
the annuity product also there are
certain other products and cohorts where
uh you have witnessed uh some challenges
uh so I wanted to get some color on what
this uh products or cohorts would be and
is it uh any particular uh mass market
strategy or any particular product uh
which is really driving this. Uh just
wanted to get some sense of how these
things can shape up let's say from the
next two to three years also. uh if you
know if your product or customer
strategies kind of were to remain the
same. Uh the second question uh was on
the banking channel. Um uh in your
opening remarks you mentioned that uh
you want to in focus on increasing your
counter share. So X of ICC bank uh you
know now that some of the um bank of
partnerships X ICC bank have kind of
increased in vintage uh could you give
some quantitative color on your counter
share or or at least the movement in
counter share over the last few years or
maybe this year. Uh and finally third
question uh is on the unit side. Uh it
seems that your unit margins have been
moving up over the last two years uh due
to the efforts that you have undertaken
be it in terms of riders or having some
issue. Uh so how much headroom uh would
you believe that you have in this
category uh to kind of further scale up
the margin profile and just one small
data keeping question if you used to
break up the unwinding into uh reference
rate and real world returns uh if you
can kind of quantify that number.
>> Yes. So that again that's alignment with
how the market is presenting it. Uh
we're not breaking the unwind up at this
point. uh in terms of persistency see
there are always going to be some
products that are doing better than the
expected uh uh persistency and some that
are doing worse. Uh the way that we've
seen this evolve is that there are
certain product and channel cohorts
where we need to do some work where the
persistency has not been in line and uh
that is the reason why we said we will
keep continue to watch these and see how
we could keep the how we could improve
these persistencies uh in the years
going forward. uh as Anu also pointed
out uh we continuously look at our
distribution and seeing what adds value.
Now very clearly if there are cohorts
that are not adding value then we look
to step away from those cohorts uh and
uh you're not able to fix them. Uh so to
that extent there is a continuous region
of our distribution uh of what customer
segments that we want to onboard through
specific distribution uh and corrective
action get taken along with our
distribution teams on the ground. uh so
I don't want to call out any specific uh
channel or any uh product but there are
some small cohorts here and there that
we need to fix and that we'll continue
to work at uh in the years as well. Uh
within the nonICC bank uh we did mention
that we've had an increase in market
share by and large uh again a lot of the
work has gone in across all of these
partnerships to be able to uh drive our
share. Uh but again it's it depends upon
each particular shop what our share is
in that particular shop. Uh but by and
large uh we've been seeing a positive
trend in terms of increasing share in
most places.
Uh coming to a question on unit length
and its uh margin. Yes you're right.
Over the years, we've been able to
improve the margin of our unit linked by
addition of high assured by elongating
terms. Uh but I think the way to look at
the unit link product is
it is a very transparent product. Uh if
you're able to add sufficient protection
to it, it makes it far more meaningful.
Uh it is not a mutual fund product. I
think that has to be very well
understood. uh by making sure that
you're adding protection and uh
propositions specifically you're able to
cater to various needs of customers and
fulfill whatever needs that they set
out. So that's been our approach to uh
product development and uh proposition
uh setup for our customers and we'll
continue to keep working at this and
uncovering your uh segments that we'd
want to expand this into.
>> All right. Uh thank you D. Just one
small uh clarification. I mean in the
postality question you mentioned that uh
you'll be working through this products
and customer cohorts uh uh incrementally
throughout the year and going ahead also
right I mean is that the right
understanding
>> that's right it's it's a continuous
exercise it's a continuous exercise like
as Anuk also pointed out there are
always going to be some segments that
are not up to par uh the point is uh you
try to fix it because you start with the
underlying proposition that is being
provided to customers uh and the sales
process uh if uh it doesn't work then uh
you stop selling.
>> Got it. Uh thank you and all the best.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you. Next question is from the
line of Nishin Sawat from Kotak. Please
go ahead.
>> Nishant your line is unmuted. Please go
ahead with your question.
>> Yeah, thanks for taking my uh my
question. uh you know just uh on the
protection side on the the retail uh the
retail term side we have seen a lot of
tailwinds to this GST and uh you know
hopefully you know we can see this this
continuing as well. Uh is it because
there is a natural offset or or as the
industry or you know interestingly you
kind of know tailored certain products
or looked at certain segments or
probably you know made more investments
to grow this segment and in that sense
probably if you could give some sense of
you know how long can this can this
continue.
So nation if the question is will have
we created new products and innovative
products answer is yes we have done that
through the year uh by providing newer
newer propositions along the way but I
think one of the biggest tailwinds that
we have got as an industry has been the
GST reform and that is felt most in
protection in retail protection because
that's where you see the 18% go off so
to the customer you're seeing this
improved benefit uh come through
immediately. In fact, this is not just
for new customers. Uh it's also
available for uh existing customers
because as they pay the renewals, the
renewals are that much cheaper.
So the way I'm looking at it is that it
has actually helped uh create positive
word of mouth on retail protection
because very clearly I think this is one
of the essences of our industry. Uh
selling protection has to become one of
the ces of what this industry does. In
fact, we called it out also in the
earlier part of our commentary. You
know, the retail summer growth for the
industry actually was two and a half
times for the reform than what it was
the pre-reform
through this financial year. So very
clearly I think everyone uh it's not
just us. Everyone has latched on to this
particular uh move and it's up to the
industry to make this a success
>> which it has for the half year that we
see.
>> Got it. Uh just now on you know I I
believe credential is setting up a
health business. So you know is there a
partnership or any synergies between uh
you know between you and and potential
or is it run completely separately?
No, I believe that's a separate company.
Sure. And if if I mean hypothetically if
wants to move from health to life, do
they need an energy from you?
>> Again, these are shareholder matters. I
think we could uh let's take the
conversation to financial results.
>> Sure. Sure. Those were my questions.
Thank you very much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you ladies and gentlemen. That was
the last question for today. I would now
like to hand the conference back to Mr.
Anu Bakshi, MD and CEO for closing
comments. Over to you, sir.
>> Thank you. Thank you very much,
everyone. Have a good day.
>> Thank you. On behalf of ICIC Predential
Life Insurance Company Limited, that
concludes this conference. Thank you for
joining us and you may now disconnect
your lines.
If you found this video helpful, please
like, share and subscribe to Con Call
India for latest upcoming con